Mark Bean

Lebanon, OH 45036 mbean0302@gmail.com 1-513-505-5204

Critical thinking Web Developer with a willingness to work in small teams or large groups collaboratively to accomplish any task.

I am well-versed in multiple programming languages, and have some experience debugging code and thinking outside the box. I have lived on a computer since I was 11 years old with my first Windows 95 machine!

I consider myself to be a lifelong learner and will never stop refining my craft. My most recent course on Udemy was a React course and I fell even more in love with development using that framework! It is now my primary focus.

Work Experience

Service Manager & BAS Integrator

Air Force One January 2021 to Present

Specializing in programming and starting up programmable logic controllers and Niagara BAS Systems, as the liaison to the Building Automation Service Department and Manager of the Service Department.

Service Technician

Comfort Solutions - Lebanon, OH January 2017 to December 2021

The Lead Service Technician is responsible for overseeing the diagnosis, maintenance, and installation of HVAC equipment.

Service Technician

Ober Gatlinburg - Gatlinburg, TN January 2016 to December 2017

An entry-level HVAC service technician is responsible for identifying and solving HVAC-related problems in building HVAC and kitchen appliances.

Education

HVAC/R Technical Degree in HVAC

Tennessee College of Applied Technology 2014 to 2016

High school diploma

Cherokee High School - Rogersville, TN 2001 to 2005

Skills

- React
- Python
- HTML/CSS/JS
- Node.js
- GitHub
- Bootstrap
- JSON

Languages

• English - Fluent

Links

https://github.com/hvacTech0302

https://mark-bean.netlify.app/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/mark-bean-619a70215

Military Service

Branch: United States Navy Service Country: United States

Rank: Petty Officer Third Class

2005 to 2009

No longer in active or inactive reserves.

Certifications and Licenses

Udemy Complete React Developer

July 2023 to Present

Using the latest version of React(React 18), this course is focused on efficiency. Never spend time on confusing, out-of-date, incomplete tutorials anymore. Graduates of Andrei's courses are now working at Google, Tesla, Amazon, Apple, IBM, JP Morgan, Meta, + other top tech companies.

Udemy Complete Python Developer

2020 to Present

It's time to become a modern and complete Python developer! Join a live online community of over 900,000+ developers and a course taught by an industry expert that has actually worked both in

Silicon Valley and Toronto.Graduates of Andrei's courses are now working at Google, Tesla, Amazon, Apple, IBM, JP Morgan, Meta, + other top tech companies.

This comprehensive and project-based coursewill introduce you to all of the modern skills of a Python developer (Python 3) and along the way, we will build over 12 real-world projects to add to your portfolio(You will get access to all the code from the 12+ projects we build, so that you can put them on your portfolio right away)!

Udemy Complete 2024 Web Developer Boot-Camp

January 2024 to Present

Welcome to the Complete Web Development Bootcamp,the only course you need to learn to code and become a full-stack web developer. With 150,000+ ratings and a 4.8 average, my Web Development course is one of the highest-rated courses in the history of Udemy!

At 62+ hours, this Web Development course is without a doubt themost comprehensiveweb development course available online. Even if you havezeroprogramming experience, this course will take you frombeginner to mastery.

Udemy JavaScript Beginner Boot-camp

2021 to Present

JavaScript the Basicsis your one stop course to enter into the language of JavaScript. We are going to start from scratch and build up our understanding of the world's most popular programming language together.

Udemy Advanced Responsive Website Design (Bootstrap 4)

2022 to Present

This course will show you how to make a complete Bootstrap 4 Template from scratchstarting with blank HTML, CSS and JavaScript files! We'll be moving rapidly to give you the quickest, yet most thorough Bootstrap website building experience possible. Once you've completed the course you'll be able to design and develop your own Bootstrap 4templates and themes.

Additional Information

I do not have any professional experience or degrees, but have done some freelance work maintaining a couple of companies' websites and have spent the last 5 years in one coding course or another online. I am ready to start a new career!